MEGAN L. HOWLEY

meglhowley@gmail.com | (781)-307-6228 | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a full stack engineer with a passion for creating applications that emphasize clean functionality and mindful design. Financial professional turned software developer, I bring 6 years of client consulting, along with a high standard for transformative UX. I strive to always have fun on my teams in order to inspire innovation.

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Javascript | Typescript | Python | React | Redux | React Native | RESTful API | GraphQL | Flask | ES6 | Node.JS | Express.JS | MongoDB Mongoose | PostGreSQL | MySQL | SQLAlchemy | JWT | OOP | Heroku | Xcode | Android Studio | Pantheon | Git | Netlify | NPM

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Portland Webworks | Full Stack Software Developer

October 2021 - Present

- React Native & Redux developer on high impact mobile application for the state of Florida's Turnpike/Tolling Enterprise SunPass
- Lead React developer for the state of Maine's Department of Education TechEd 'Learn with Moose' program, launched as a response for educators to create content for PreK-12 during the COVID-19 pandemic
- Collaborates with UX designers, QA engineers, and Product Managers using an agile approach for project management, operating on 2 week sprints within Jira. Peer reviewed pull requests and wrote high quality code to stand up to peer review.
- <u>Front end technologies</u>: React Native, React, Typescript, Redux, Tailwind, Ant Design and Material UI Kits, CSS, and Sass. Created highly tested, reusable, and maintainable code with Jest for unit testing
- Back end technologies: Java / Springboot, GraphQL, Docker, MySQL. AWS / S3 for cloud hosting

General Assembly | Software Engineering Fellow

April 2021 - August 2021

- 500-hour full-time 12 week course gaining hands-on industry experience in working with various front-end and back-end technologies.
 Projects built:
 - Bop It! Virtual: Ignite your nostalgia with this Vanilla JS game modeled after the beloved 90's Hasbro toy. Game was built with Vanilla JS and pure CSS only, in the DOM land
 - HikeME: Interactive full-stack hiking application that allows users to browse Maine's best trails. Trail data includes: GoogleMaps location data, elevation gain, length, trail difficulty, weather conditions, and more. PERN Stack Postgres, Express, React, Node
 - 20TRENDY: Full-stack capstone project leveraging a python API, pyTrends, on the back end. Allows users to search trending
 internet searches at different intervals throughout the historic year 2020. Stack- Python/Flask, Postgres, Express, Redux, Node.js

Fidelity Investments | Fidelity Brokerage Services LLC

March 2016 - April 2021

Fidelity Institutional | Institutional Client Manager

- Lead point of contact for one of Fidelity's largest institutional clients, with nearly 90B in assets under management. Provided operational and technical support to this registered investment advisory (RIA) firm
- Partnered with outside institutions' trading team to ensure smooth data integration between shareholder systems
- Troubleshooted trading related issues weekly and was team lead on all equity and mutual fund trade corrections
- Onboarded and hosted trainings for the RIA's new employees, via both travel and remote trainings, on how to navigate through Fidelity's various advisory user applications and how to submit requests to the back office.

Fidelity Brokerage Services | Investment Consultant

- Provided needs-based mentorship to mass affluent customers, contributing to the long-term growth of Fidelity assets
- With Fidelity's open architecture, provided a wide broad range of financial products and services.
- Deepened client knowledge on mutual funds, ETFs, and long-term planning concepts to retain and grow company's assets.

Fidelity Personal Investing | Relationship Manager

- Managed high net worth client relationships for 2 books of clients totaling 2.5 Billion
- Drove client engagement through proactive contact strategies using polished and professional communication skills
- Partnered with planners to provide clients and their families holistic financial planning including estate, trust, education, retirement, and wealth planning

EDUCATION

BS (Bachelor of Science) | University of Vermont | Burlington, VT | Finance with Mathematics Minor || Cum Laude Cardiff Business School | Cardiff, Wales, UK | Bilateral Exchange Program || International Finance General Assembly | Boston, MA | Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp || 420 Hour Certificate